Dral Alexey (surname, firstname) Founder & CEO at <u>BigData Team</u> phone number: +7 920 655 1027 e-mail: aadral@bigdatateam.org

Summary

10 year working experience for the top Russian and international companies, including Amazon AWS, Yandex, Sberbank, Rambler and qualification on large-scale problems, leading R&D teams, defining strategy for the whole departments build up a great mentor with an aspiration to offer insights to my students. Therefore, I teach around the globe, launch new onsite and online courses to reduce the gap between industry and academia, supervise Data Science and Data Engineering initiatives. For instance, I am personally responsible for Al RoadMap at one of the biggest Russian financial institutes.

BigData Team provides 3 types of services: online course development, in-campus course development and BigData & Machine Learning research, development and consultations. Our partners are the market leaders. For instance:

- Yandex the biggest Russian search engine company. We collaborate on online course development. See "<u>Big Data for Data Engineers</u>" Coursera specialization.
- We provide courses and give lectures on Big Data and Machine Learning for top Russian universities (MSU, HSE, MIPT, ...) as well as for corporate clients (Sberbank, Megafon, ...).
 Our courses available on English (<u>Harbour.Space University</u>). Our company is the educational partner of University.2035 (CDO track, Russian Digital Economy program).
- We collaborate on chatbot development with one of the biggest Russian pharmacy companies (private). We helped to scale blockchain platform (startup, private). We helped to build Al RoadMap (financial institute, private).

Major conferences 2017-2018

- 2018, Eastern Economic Forum, CDO Education, "Data Culture" and "Data Governance"
- 2018, Global Business Insight & Analytics Forum, "Understanding Traditional, Big Data and Emerging Analytical Architectures"
- 2018, OpenTalks, "Higher IT Education: The Challenge"
- 2017, The Second International Conference "More Than Just Learning", "Soft and Digital Skills Learning: In Search of a Balance"
- 2017, World Festival of Youth and Students, Data Science Secrets
- 2017, ACM ICPC Workshops (at Harbour Space), "Workshop on BigData"

Education

[2016] Certified Scrum Master

[2010-2012] YSDA, MSc., Computer Science, https://yandexdataschool.com/about [2005-2010] MSU, Specialias (cum laude), Mathematics, https://www.msu.ru/en/

Work experience

05.2017 - Present

Founder & CEO, BigData Team

- Lead the team of highly-qualified professionals in the field of software development (Big Data and Machine Learning)
- Head of "<u>Big Data for Data Engineers</u>" Coursera specialization (authored by Yandex)

	- Budgeting / planning
Corp University Sberbank 09.2017 - 03.2018 SBERBANK	Head of Data Science School - Responsible for IT courses and educational initiatives (Big Data, Data Science / Engineering/ Governance) - Launched internal Machine Learning course Launched series of lectures on practical data analysis with the best Russian IT-specialists (RetailRocket, Rambler, Teradata, Yandex)
PAMCS ¹ MIPT 11.2016 - 09.2017 APT DIHT ² MIPT, Senior Lecturer 02.2014 - Present	Deputy Director of Research and Innovations - Attract industrial companies to outsource research to phystech-school laboratories - Review existing and develop new IT courses and educational initiatives (e.g. online programs) - Helped to launch R&D laboratory MIPT-Sberbank (responsible for business proposal and budgeting) Head of BigData and Machine Learning / Senior Lecturer - Responsible for courses on BigData and Machine Learning for BSc. and MSc. students (educate over 400 students / year)
Amazon Web Services 01.2015 - 10.2016 amazon web services	Software Engineer - Develop Frameworks for network automation. Support Customers (30+ teams) across the 24h time zone (e.g. Sydney, Dublin, Seattle). Got award (from VP-level) for internal network automation framework development. - Negotiate software requirements with vendors. - Author of a code-free automation tool for Network Engineers - Reduce release time from days to hours by introducing continuous deployment - Development Mentor, author of internal Python course
Yandex 11.2013 - 11.2014 Yandex	Senior SDE / Team Lead - E-commerce Recommender Systems development (algorithms, architecture, prototypes and production versions). In particular, I was responsible for up-sales and cross-sales increase at Yandex.Market. Yandex.Market has 1+ million visitors per day and 50+ million of unique items. I have increased CTR by +5+30% and revenue by 10% (depends on recommendation block) I have built Recommender System engine and launched the first online experiment within 2 months.

R&D positions at ABBYY, Rambler, Yandex, ...

2007 - 2013

¹ PAMCS = Phystech-school of Applied Mathematics and Computer Science ² DIHT = Department of Innovation and High Technology;